hey it's Brett Contreras this is a quick
video to go over neck packing because I
think a lot of people don't understand
it and don't know why it's important so
first I want to explain what is neck
packing and then why should you care
right so neck packing is this cervical
region and capital flexion which just
means you're trying to make a double
chin so I'm basically gonna move my you
retrieve my cervical spine wall flexing
my head forward so just like this okay
it looks really nerdy it feels really
stupid to do it but it's important when
you exercise but when you look at when
you see pictures of you know Olympic
weightlifters and and watch videos of
powder lifters most of them don't pack
their neck you know we've been taught to
look up or look you know when we're
lifting most people who may set up for
the devil they're kind of like this and
they'll be looking forward you know a
lot of us old-timers if you've been
around for a while you've been talking
to look up when you squat or you know
look straight ahead or when you deadlift
or I like to look at myself in the
mirror when I deadlift so what you end
up doing the end up hyper extending your
cervical spine which is not I mean think
about it it's just not wise it's not the
safest way and it might even you know it
not be optimal for power production so
when if you've already been lifting this
way for years and you don't have
problems you probably don't need to
start packing your neck but if you're a
trainer or a straight coach and someone
comes to you and they're green why not
teach them from from day one how to pack
their neck so I'll show you what it
looks like when you're dead looking all
right basically
what I like to do when I deadlift I look
at myself in the mirror and I check to
make sure like now you can read my shirt
and then and then this way I know that
I'm arching my back and my chest is up
but then I make sure that my neck is
back because it looks like this okay
this means I marched a good arch no
double chin right so you can do this in
anything that involves a hip hinge so
you know rear delt raises bent over rows
anything like that you can pack the neck
just means make a double chin in
cervical region paired with capital
flexion which is just a fancy way of
saying make a double chin
keeps your neck in alignment it's safer
and it could help with power production
I'm not sure what I think about in terms
of Olympic lifting because I just don't
know I haven't really thought about it
enough but for deadlifting you know bent
over rows rear delt raises things like
that anything that involves a hip hinge
and it's kind of like strength work
definitely neck packing is the way to go
thanks for watching